
<li>Diversification in Indian agriculture towards high-value crops: Multilevel determinants and policy implications
 Authors : Pratap S. Birthal, Jaweriah Hazrana, Digvijay S. Negi (2020), Land Use Policy https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0264837719312578</li>
<li>Back to the plough: Women managers and farm productivity in India
 Author :Kanika Mahajan World Development,Vol 124,2019</li>
<li>A multilevel analysis of drought risk in Indian agriculture: Implications for managing risk at different geographical levels
 Authors :Pratap S. Birthal, Jaweriah Hazrana, Digvijay Singh Negi, (2019) Climatic Change https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10584-019-02573-9</li>
<li>Farmers’ choice of market channels and producer prices in India: Role of transportation and communication networks
 Author :Digvijay Singh Negi, Pratap S. Birthal, Devesh Roy, Md. Tajuddin Khan (2018) Food Policy, 2018</li>
<li>MEASURING WHAT MATTERS IN AGRICULTURE AND FOOD SYSTEMS A synthesis of the results and recommendations of TEEB for Agriculture and Food’s Scientific and Economic Foundations Report.
 Author :Pengue, Walter &amp; Muller, Alexander &amp; Sukhdev, Pavan &amp; Gemmill Herren, Barbara &amp; Gundimeda, Haripriya &amp; Hamm, Michael &amp; Hussain, Salman &amp; Lobos Alba, Ivonne &amp; May, Peter &amp; Obst, Carl &amp; Sandhu, Harpindher &amp; Tirado, Cristina &amp; Zhang, Wei. (2018) </li>
<li>TEEBAgriFood methodology: an overview of evaluation and valuation methods and tools. InTEEB for Agriculture &amp; Food: Scientific and Economic Foundations
 Author :Gundimeda, H., Markandya, A. and Bassi, A.M. (2018) Geneva: UN Environment. Chapter 7, 247-295</li>
<li>Child Welfare Programs and Child Nutrition: Evidence from a Mandated School Meal Program.
 Author :Farzana Afridi. Journal of Development Economics, 92(2):152-165, Reprinted in ‘The Economics of Food Security‘, <a href="http://www.e-elgar.com/shop/books?book_series=417"><span style="color: #eb058f;">The International Library of Critical Writings in Economics series </a>Vol II, eds.Raghbendra Jha and Rajiv Gaiha,November 2016, Edward Elgar.</li>
<li><a href="http://192.168.1.43/~cecfee/incremental_reforms.pdf"><span style="color: #eb058f;">Incremental Food Policy Reforms; What are the Possibilities?</a>
  Authors : B Ramaswami and Milind Murugkar in S. Mahendra Dev and P. G. Babu (Ed.,) Development in India: Micro and Macro Perspectives, Springer: New Delhi, 2015, 125-153.</li>
<li><a href="http://192.168.1.43/~cecfee/The_State_and_the_Market_in_the_Delivery_of_Food_Subsidy.pdf"><span style="color: #eb058f; font-size: 12pt;">Delivering Food Subsidy: The State and the Market</a>
  Authors : A. Kotwal and B. Ramaswami, in R. Herring (ed.,) The Oxford Handbook of Food, Politics and Society, 301-326, Oxford University Press, 2015.</li>
<li>Biogas: Clean energy access with low-cost mitigation of global warming.
 Authors : E Somanathan, Randall Bluffstone. Environmental and Resource Economics (2015). 62: 265–277.</li>
<li><span style="color: #eb058f; font-size: 12pt;"><a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/abstract_S1355770X13000326"><span style="color: #eb058f;">The Informational and Signaling Impacts of Labels: Experimental Evidence from India on GM Foods
 </a>Discussion Paper
  Authors : Bharat Ramaswami, Sangeeta Bansal and Sujoy Chakravarty</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sagepub.in/books/Book240411/toc#tabview=toc"><span style="color: #eb058f; font-size: 12pt;">The Percolation of Public Expenditure: Food Subsidies and the Poor in India and the Philippines</a>
 Discussion Paper
 Authors : Shikha Jha and Bharat Ramaswami</li>
<li><span style="color: #eb058f; font-size: 12pt;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="http://www.isid.ac.in/~pu/dispapers/dp11-04.pdf">Cash Transfers to Individuals based on Biometric Identification are Feasible and will bring Large Gains to the Economically Insecure</a>
 Authors : Arka Roy Chaudhuri and E. Somanathan</li>
<li>The Distributional Impact of Climate Change: Why Food Prices Matter.
  Authors : E Somanathan, Eshita Gupta and Bharat Ramaswami</li>
<li><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0305750X21001510?dgcid=author"><span><span style="font-family: georgia, palatino, serif;">Electrification and cooking fuel choice in rural India</a>
 Authors : Ridhima Gupta, Martino Pelli ,World Development,Volume 146,2021,105539</li>
<li>Welfare impacts of transport fuel price changes on Indian households: An application of LA-AIDS model
 Authors : Dhanyashree Bhuvandas, Haripriya Gundimeda(2020), Energy Policy, volume 144, September, 111583</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 12pt; color: #eb058f;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0973082617306683?via%3Dihub">Are renewable energy subsidies in Nepal reaching the poor?</a>
 Author : Dipendra Bhattarai, E Somanathan and Mani Nepal. Energy for Sustainable Development(2018). 43: 114–122.</li>
<li>Surprises up the energy ladder.
 Authors :Andrew Pascale, Shoibal Chakravarty, Paul Lant, Simon Smart and Chris Graig Nepal.(March,2017).</li>
<li>Is Solar power cheaper than Coal?
 Authors :Mitavachan, H., Chakravarty, S.Current Science 109(12), 2180-2181.</li>
<li>Biogas: Clean energy access with low-cost mitigation of global warming.
 Authors : E Somanathan and Randall Bluffstone. Environmental and Resource Economics (2015). 62: 265–277.</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 12pt; color: #eb058f;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="http://www.isid.ac.in/~pu/dispapers/dp14-05.pdf">The Effect of Development on the Climate Sensitivity of Electricity Demand in India</a>
 Author : Eshita Gupta</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 12pt; color: #eb058f;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0140988312001016">Global Warming and Electricity Demand in the Rapidly Growing City of Delhi: a Semi-Parametric Variable Coefficient Approach</a>
 Author : Eshita Gupta</li>
<li>Rethinking sustainability: From seafood consumption to seafood commons.
 Authors : Divya Karnad, Dhruv Gangadharan, Yarlagadda Chaitanya Krishna. Elsevier Geoforum Vol 126, Pages 26-36 (2021).</li>
<li>Why Regulations come up short? Some observations from a field study of the Kanpur Leather Industry, Ecology, Economy and Society.
 Authors :Aparajita Singh and Haripriya Gundimeda .INSEE journal, 3(2), 185-90(2020).</li>
<li><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10113-020-01637-2"><span>Does Mangrove Plantation Reduce Coastal Erosion? Assessment from the West Coast of India</a>
 Author: <span style="color: #808080;">Saudamini Das<span style="color: #808080;">(2020) (<a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs10113-020-01670-1">Correction</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0305750X20300917"><span><span>Value of cleaner neighborhoods: Application of hedonic price model in low income context</a>
 Authors : Mani Nepal, Rajesh K. Rai, Madan S. Khadayat and E. Somanathan (2020).</li>
<li>What the Economy Needs Now 
 Authors :Abhijit Banerjee, Pranjul Bhandari, Sajjid Chinoy, Maitreesh Ghatak, Gita Gopinath, Amartya Lahiri, Neelkanth Mishra, Prachi Mishra, Karthik Muralidharan, Rohini Pande, Eswar Prasad, E. Somanathan, and Raghuram Rajan.(2019). </li>
<li>Valuing water provisioning service of Broadleaf and Chir Pine forests in the Himalayan region 
 Authors :Das, Saudamini, Mani Nepal, Rajesh K. Rai , Laxmi D. Bhatta &amp; Madan S. Khadayat(2019). Forest Policy and Economics, 105, 40-51 (2019). doi.org/10.1016/j.forpol.2019.05.017. </li>
<li>Biodiversity/ecosystem services scenario exercises from the Asia–Pacific: typology, archetypes and implications for sustainable development goals (SDGs).
 Authors :Rajarshi DasGupta, Shizuka Hashimoto, Haripriya Gundimeda.Sustainability Science 2019, 14 (1), 241-257. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11625-018-0647-1.</li>
<li>An integrated assessment of vulnerability of floods using composite index – A district level analysisfor Bihar, India.
 Authors :Rupak Kumar Jha,Haripriya Gundimeda (2019).International Journal of Disaster Risk Reduction 35 (2019). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijdrr.2019.101074.</li>
<li>Why Coping Cost is An Underestimate of Willingness to Pay? Some Theoretical Explanations Based on Forest Water Link 
 Authors : Bansal, G &amp; Das, Saudamini (2018) Applied Economics &amp; Business, 2(2), 1-14. Available at: http://aeb.wyb.ac.lk/index.php/vol2issue2/</li>
<li>Does Collective Action Sequester Carbon? Evidence from the Nepal Community Forestry Program.
 Authors : E Somanathan, Prakash Jha, Harisharan Luintel, Rajesh Bista, Michael Toman, Naya Paudel (2018). World Development. doi : 101: 133-141</li>
<li>Valuing Cultural Services of the Kailash Sacred Landscape for Sustainable Management
 Authors : M Nepal, R Rai, S Das, L Bhatta, R Kotru, M Khadayat, R Rawal, G Negi (2018) Sustainability  10 (10), 3638</li>
<li>Forest dependence and poverty in the Himalayas—Differences between India and Nepal
 Authors : P Shyamsundar, S Das, M Nepal (2018)  Ecology, Economy and Society  205-223 </li>
<li>Biodiversity/ecosystem services scenario exercises from the Asia–Pacific: typology, archetypes and implications for sustainable development goals (SDGs)
 Authors : DasGupta, R., Hashimoto, S. &amp; Gundimeda, H. (2018)  Sustainability Science  10.1007/s11625-018-0647-1 </li>
<li>Have the Special Economic Zones Succeeded in Attracting FDI?—Analysis for India
 Authors : DasGupta, R., Hashimoto, S. &amp; Gundimeda, H. (2018)  Theoretical Economics Letters  10.1007/s11625-018-0647-1 </li>
<li>Greening offices: Willingness to pay for green-certified office spaces in Bengaluru, India.
 Authors : Abraham, P. S., &amp; Gundimeda, H. (2018)  Environment, Development and Sustainability. doi:10.1007/s10668-018-0265-1 </li>
<li>Encouraging the urban households to segregate the waste they generate: insights from a field experiment in Delhi, India
 Authors : Wadehra, S and Mishra A (2018)  Resources, Conservation and Recycling  Volume 134, pp 239-247 </li>
<li>Summary for policymakers of the regional assessment report on biodiversity and ecosystem services for Asia and the Pacific of the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services
 Authors : Karki, Madhav &amp; Senaratna Sellamuttu, S &amp; Okayasu, S &amp; Suzuki, W &amp; A. Acosta, L &amp; Alhafedh, Y &amp; Anticamara, Jonathan &amp; Ausseil, Anne-Gaelle &amp; Davies, K &amp; Gasparatos, Alexandros &amp; Gundimeda, Haripriya &amp; Faridah-Hanum, I &amp; Kohsaka, R &amp; Kumar, R &amp; Managi, S &amp; Wu, N &amp; Rajvanshi, Asha &amp; Rawat, Gopal &amp; Riordan, Philip &amp; C. Youn, Y. (2018)  IPBES (2018)  </li>
<li>Global warming and local air pollution have reduced wheat yields in India.
 Authors : Ridhima Gupta, E. Somanathan and Sagnik Dey (2017). Climatic Change. doi:140(3-4): 593-604</li>
<li>Biogas: Clean energy access with low-cost mitigation of global warming.
 Authors : E Somanathan, Randall Bluffstone. Environmental and Resource Economics (2015). 62: 265–277.</li>
<li>Conserving forests for biodiversity – status and trends from the global forest resource assessment 2015.
 Authors : E Somanathan, David Morales-Hidalgo and Sonja N. Oswalt. Forest Ecology and Management (2015), 352: 68-77.</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 12pt; color: #eb058f;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0378112715003370">Status and trends in global primary forest, protected areas, and areas designated for conservation of biodiversity from the Global Forest Resources Assessment 2015</a>
  Authors : David Morales-Hidalgo, Sonja N. Oswalt, E. Somanathan</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 12pt; color: #eb058f;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="http://www.iwaponline.com/wp/up/wp2013002.htm">Are Embankments a Good Flood-Control Strategy? A Case Study of the Kosi River</a>
 Discussion Paper
 Author : E. Somanathan</li>
<li><span style="color: #eb058f;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="http://reep.oxfordjournals.org/content/4/2/275.short">Effects of Information on Environmental Quality in Developing Countries</a>
 Discussion Paper
 Author : E. Somanathan </li>
<li><span style="color: #eb058f;"><a style="color: #eb058f;" href="http://www.pnas.org/content/106/11/4143.short">Decentralization for Cost effective Conservation</a>
 Authors : E. Somanathan, R. Prabhakar and Bhupendra Singh Mehta </li>
<li>Community Managed Forest Groups and Preferences for REDD+ Contract Attributes: A choice experiment survey of communities in Nepal.
 Authors : E Somanathan, Sahan T. M. Dissanayake, Prakash Jha, Bhim Adhikari, Rajesh Bista, Randall Bluffstone, Harisharan Luintel, Peter Martinsson, Naya Sharma Paudel, Michael Toman. <p></p>
<p></p>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 12pt; color: #a808a8;"><a style="color: #a808a8;" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0095069622000602">Access to toilets and violence against women</a>
  Authors: Md Amzad Hossain, Kanika Mahajan, and Sheetal Sherkri. Journal of Environmental Economics and Management, July 2022.DOI:<a style="color: #3366ff;" href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jeem.2022.102695">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jeem.2022.102695</a> </li>
<li><span style="color: #800080; font-size: 12pt;"> <a style="color: #800080;" href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fonlinelibrary.wiley.com%2Fdoi%2Ffull%2F10.1002%2Fhec.4514&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AOvVaw0JW2nf-pzEXe3JrIuPP3Mb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fonlinelibrary.wiley.com%252Fdoi%252Ffull%252F10.1002%252Fhec.4514%26sa%3DD%26sntz%3D1%26usg%3DAOvVaw0JW2nf-pzEXe3JrIuPP3Mb&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1657087784324000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2Y5gx9B2E9LVBbpIiWR3li">Coping with the Consequences of Short-Term Illness Shocks: The Role of Intra-Household Labor Substitution</a>
Authors: Abhishek Dureja and Digvijay S. Negi (2022), Health Economics.
<a style="color: #3366ff;" href="https://doi.org/10.1002/hec.4514">https://doi.org/10.1002/hec.4514 </a>   </li>
<li>“<a href="https://ecoinsee.org/journal/ojs/index.php/ees/article/view/373/141">A Report on the 14th Annual Meeting of the Environment for Development (EfD) Initiative</a>”
 Authors : E. Somanathan, T. R. Bhatt, and V. Chowdhury_Ecology, Economy and Society – the INSEE Journal_, 4(1): 157-160, Jan 2021.</li>
<li>“Karl-Göran Mäler: the _Adi-Guru_ of Environmental Economics.”
 Authors : Das Saudamini_Ecology, Economy and Society – the INSEE Journal_, 3(2): 223–226, July2020. DOI :<a href="https://doi.org/10.37773/ees.v3i2.269" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://doi.org/10.37773/ees.v3i2.269&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1595481055367000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE_X-neIAcOKvvUOVQpMklEz93B0w">https://doi.org/10.37773/ees.<wbr>v3i2.269</a></li>
<li><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11205-020-02372-1">Gendered Well-Being: Cross-Sectional Evidence from Poor Urban Households in India</a>
 Authors : Sutirtha Bandyopadhyay Social Indicators Research (2020) </li>
<li><a href="https://www.epw.in/journal/2020/15/notes/manufacturing-slowdown-india.html">New Evidence from a Double Deflation Approach Manufacturing Slowdown in India</a>
 Authors : Sutirtha Bandyopadhyay, Rahul Nilakantan Economic and Political Weekyl, Vol. 55, Issue No. 15, 11 Apr, 2020 </li>
<li>Gender differences in health expenditure of rural Cancer Patients: Evidence from a Public tertiary care facility in India
 Authors :A Batra, I Gupta, A Mukhopadhyay (2018) Journal of Quantitative Economics 16 (3), 615-629</li>
<li>Redistributing teachers using local transfers
 Authors :A Mukhopadhyay, AthisiiKayina and Anugula Reddy (2018)  World Development. doi: 10.1016/j.worlddev.2018.06.010</li>
<li>Improving learning outcomes through information provision: Experimental evidence from Indian villages
 Authors :F Afridi, B Barooah, R Somanathan (2018)  Journal of Development Economics. doi:10.1016/j.jdeveco.2018.08.002</li>
<li>Editorial Introduction to Special Issue on “Gender, Family and Development”
 Authors :R Somanathan (2018) Journal of Demographic Economics 84(1), 1-2. doi:10.1017/dem.2018.4</li>
<li>Why are fewer married women joining the work force in rural India? A decomposition analysis over two decades
 Authors :F Afridi, T Dinkelman, K Mahajan (2018) Journal of Population Economics 31 (3), 783-818</li>
<li>The Measurement and Mismeasurement of Social Difference
 Authors :R Somanathan (2018) ideas.repec.org</li>
<li>Social Security with Differential Mortality
 Authors :M.Bishnu, N. Guo,C. S. Kumru (2018) Journal of Macroeconomics</li>
<li>Deterring kickbacks and encouraging entry in public procurement markets: Evidence from firm surveys in 90 developing countries
 Authors :Knack, S., Biletska, N.,Kacker, K. World Bank Economic Review: https://doi.org/10.1093/wber/lhy016 </li>
<li>Is economic growth linked with comprehensive wealth? Link to state-level analysis in India in S. Managi and P. Kumar edited, Inclusive wealth report 2018 – Measuring Progress towards sustainability
 Authors :Haripriya Gundimeda  Tawlor and Francis </li>
<li>What’s in a definition? A study on the suitability of the current urban definition in India through its employment guarantee programme
 Authors :Vaidehi Tandel, Komal Hiranandani, Mudit Kapoor (2018)  Journal of Asian Economics: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asieco.2018.11.001</li>